本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：鱼      校对：小路     时间轴：虫不知
特效：Will      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
■
怎么了
What's up?
该死的
Damn, bitch.
有何收获
Got something for me?
我找到他们了
Yeah, I found them.
这是5还是S
Is this a 5 or an S?
不  慢着  S
No, wait. S.
哦对  是5
Yeah, a 5.
神啊  你怎么连"street"(街)
Jesus, how the hell do you spell
都能拼成"streat"
"street" wrong?S-T-R-E-A-T?
兄弟
Hey, man.
我可是拼了命的散货收钱
I'm slinging mad volume and fat-stacking
聪明蛋  你懂我意思吗
Benjis, you know what I'm saying?
我可不是全知全能的  连拼写那种傻事都会
I can't be all about,like, spelling and shit.
有名字吗
So they got names?
她的名字  恩  我不知道
Hers is, like, I don't know.
只知道她是个女人
She's just this woman is all.
男的  别人叫他精虫
Him they call Spooge.
精虫
Spooge?
不是疯狗  也不是猛男
Not Mad Dog, not Diesel?
我就直说吧  你被抢了
So let me get this straight.You got jacked
还是被一个叫精虫的人
by a guy named Spooge?
这关他的名字什么事
Yo, what's his name matter?
我满眼尽是他的刀
All's I saw was that knife
那么大一把直抵着我的脸
he stuck in my face, like that big!
但如果你是在找不做这事儿的理由的话
But if you're looking for a reason not to go do this thing...
-我有那么说么  -我就自己去做  行了吧
- Did I say that?  - 'Cause I'll go do it myself, right?
我只是还在假释期
It's just I'm on probation and all.
就是说你打算做咯
So you gonna do it?
很好  不错
Good. Right on.
这两个人得好好修理修理
'Cause these two, they need to get got.
绝
命
毒
师
第二季
第六集
混蛋  我的钱呢
Where's my money, bitch?
我的钱在哪
Where's my money?
这样不错
That's good.
快开门
Come on.
我会整死你的
I will mess you up.
你准备这么玩吗  悉听尊便
Is that how you want to play this? Your call.
你的死期到了  杰克
Your funeral, Jack.
我发飙起来  可是会把你活埋了
I will bury you 'cause I'm crazy.
你知道的  疯子马乔
You know. Mucho loco.
别考验我耐心
Do not test me.
-早上好  -早上好
- Good morning!  - Good morning.
亲爱的  你挡住邮箱了
Honey, you blocking the mailbox.
抱歉
Sorry.
今天天气不错  是吗
I think it's gonna be a nice day, huh?
恩  最高也就21度
Yeah, High 70s.
祝你一天顺利
You have a great day.
好的  你也一样
Right on. You too.
他妈的
God! Shit!
有人在家吗
Anybody home?
今晚  你会收到
Tonight, you will receive
终极刀具组合
the ultimate fixture of cutlery.
今晚  在这套钢制神器中
Tonight, in this steel knockout...
嘿  家里其他人呢
Yo, is anybody else home?
你的父母呢  他们在这吗
Where's your folks? They here?
你叫什么
What's your name?
我叫
My name's...
猛男
Diesel.
嘿  你不想看看其他节目吗
Yo, don't you want to watch something other than this?
比如说  《罗杰斯先生》
Like, I don't know, Mr. Rogers?
你父母什么时候回家
So when your folks coming home?
你爸爸  精虫先生
Your dad, Mr. Spooge?
他什么时候回来
When is he getting back?
我饿了
I'm hungry.
好啊  你们一家子
Hey there, you three.
我只是想祝沃尔特第一天上班顺利归来
Just wanted to wish Walt a good first day back.
我们在想
We'll be thinking about you
你会教原子价和共有原子价还有
teaching valences and covalences and...
好吧  我大概就记得这些了  祝好运
Okay, that's officially all I remember. Good luck.
斯凯勒有空给我打个电话
Skyler, give me a call when you get a chance.
好啊  沃尔特和斯凯勒  我是格雷琴·施瓦兹
Hi, Walt and Skyler. This is Gretchen Schwartz,
只是打声招呼
Just calling to say hello.
我今天从圣达菲过来
I'm down from Santa Fe today,
立即就想到了你们俩
And I was just thinking about you both,
希望一切都好
Hoping everything's well.
我试着打沃尔特的手机
I tried Walt's cell, and it said
但他的号码无法接通
The number had been disconnected,
所以我希望一切都好
So I'm just hoping that everything's okay.
方便的时候给我回个电话
Call me if you can, whenever's convenient.
我是斯凯勒·怀特
This is Skyler White.
我是不是打扰你了
Am I catching you at a bad time?
没  完全没有
No, not at all.
接到你的电话太好了
It's so good to hear from you.
家人都好吗
How is everybody?
很好 谢谢关心
Very well, thank you.
沃尔特今天去上班了
Walt is actually at work today.
这是他第一天回去工作
It's his first day back at work,
他丢了手机  有一阵子了
And he lost his cell phone quite a while back.
真希望我们没让你操心
And I really hope we didn't worry you.
不会  这太好了
No No.I'm just so glad to hear that
大家都好  太棒了
Everybody's fine. That's wonderful.
很抱歉我现在才告诉你
I'm so very, very long overdue in telling you this,
但是我得遵守和沃尔特之间约定
And I just have to take Walt at his word
他把这事儿托付给我了
That he's been passing it along for me.
他是那么执着地
I mean, he's been so adamant about
想一个人处理这件事
Wanting to handle this whole thing by himself.
一直都想跟你通话
But I have picked up the phone
但是每次一拿起电话  我就
about a hundred times. I just...
-怎么了  -我
- What is it?  - I can't...
都不知道怎么感谢
begin to thank you and Elliott
你和埃利奥特所做的事了
For what you've done.
沃尔特的治疗费
The money for Walt's treatment, it's just...
拯救了整个家
It's saved us.
我不知道自己是否
I don't know if I...
沃尔特总是说
Walt keeps saying,
"别打扰他们了  这没什么"
"Don't bother them.It's no big deal."
但这真的很重要
But it is a big deal.
对我来说
To me.
对我们所有人来说
And to all of us.
所以我
So I just...
最终决定要
finally wanted to...
对你说声谢谢
say thank you.
说完了
Anyway.End of speech
希望我们能很快再见面
So, I do hope we get to see you soon.
说真的  无论什么时候你来
Truly, anytime you're in town,
任何时候都行
anytime at all is good for us.
今天下午怎么样
How about this afternoon?
单烯烃
Monoalkenes,
二烯烃
diolefins,
三烯烃  聚烯烃
trienes, polyenes.
光这些专有名词就够让你晕头转向了
The nomenclature alone is enough to make your head spin.
但当你不知所措的时候  你只要
But when you start to feel overwhelmed, and you will,
牢记一个元素
just keep in mind that one element.
碳
Carbon.
碳是一切的关键
Carbon is at the center of it all.
没有碳就没有生命
There is no life without carbon.
在我们所知道的宇宙中  碳元素无处不在
Nowhere. That we know of in the universe.
一切有生命的
Everything that lives,
死去的  即将诞生的
lived, will live.
都是碳元素组成的
Carbon.
卡门是碳元素组成的
Carmen is carbon.
抱歉  卡门副校长
Sorry. Assistant Principal Carmen.
你有没有
Did you...
我喜欢这么想
I like to think of it...
我认为钻石
I like to think that the diamond
和戴着钻石的女人
and the woman who wears it on her finger
都是由
are both formed
同一元素组成的
from the same stuff.
不如说钻石和发明钻石的男人
Or, say the diamond and the man who invented it.
你们感兴趣了  不是吗
That got your attention, right?
发明钻石的男人
The man who invented the diamond.
好吧
All right.
H·特雷西·霍尔  记下这个名字
H. Tracy Hall. Write this name down.
霍尔教授发明了第一个
Dr. Hall invented the first
可再生工艺用于制造人造钻石
reproducible process for making synthetic diamonds.
这是早在五十年代的事情  而如今
I mean, this is way back in the '50s.Now, today,
人造钻石被应用于石油钻探
synthetic diamonds are used in oil drilling,
电子设备等数十亿美元的产业
electronics, multi-billion dollar industries.
那时候  霍尔教授  在为通用电气工作
At the time, Dr. Hall worked for General Electric.
并为他们带来了一笔不小的财富
And he made them a fortune.
不可计数的财富
I mean, incalculable.
你们想知道通用怎么回报霍尔博士的吗
You want to know how GE rewarded Dr. Hall?
十美元的储蓄公债
A $10 US Savings Bond.
一个印在碳基纸上的储蓄公债
A Savings Bond printed on carbon-based paper
付给了一个碳基的人
paid to a carbon-based man
以奖励他以碳元素为基础的
for something he made out of...
发明
carbon.
你回来真是太好了  沃尔特
It's so nice to have you back with us, Walt.
顺便说下  你看起来真不赖
And you're looking great, by the way.
瘦了点  这当然不算坏事
A little skinnier. Which is definitely no tragedy.
-还有头发  -我其实挺喜欢那样
- And then there's the hair thing. - I actually like that.
你这造型挺不错
That's a great look for you.
你身体感觉好吗
But you're feeling good?
当然  非常好
Absolutely. 100%.
我很高兴能回来工作
I'm glad to be back at work.
我很高兴
I'm glad to...
在这儿挺开心  真的
I'm happy to be here. Really.
我们也很开心
We're happy too.
只是
And I just...
没事
It's good.
这很好
It's great.
有什么事吗
Is everything okay?
请放心
Just please feel comfortable
如果有任何问题
coming to me
就来找我
with any problems,
无论什么
Any issues.
任何事情
Anything at all.
完全保密
You know, completely confidential.
-再见 弗林  -再见 杰弗里
- See you tomorrow, Flynn.  - See you, Jeffrey.
让我看看
Let me see it.
老爸  让我看看
Dad, let me see it.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
我们走吧
Let's go.
看不见
Peekaboo.
你待在这儿别动  好吗
You stay right here, all right?
我说真的
I mean it.
-闭嘴  -你才闭嘴
- You shut up!  - You shut up!
是你把他弄丢了
You're the one who dropped it.
我没弄丢  我他妈没弄丢!
I didn't drop it! I didn't drop shit!
-是你弄丢的  -你他妈给我闭嘴
- You dropped it!  - Shut the hell up about it.
-你闭嘴  -不 你才闭嘴
- You shut up!  - No, you shut up!
起来
Get up!
闭嘴
Shut up!
你们俩都是
Both of you!
你知道可能是谁干的吗
You know who might have done it?
我大概知道
I have an idea.
我也是这么想的
Here's what I think.
你告诉我他们是谁  然后
You ID them.  And then together,
我和你一起给他们头上套上袋子
You and I put a bag over their heads.
把他们捆起来
We tie them up,
把他们运到沙漠里
Drive them way out into the desert,
再剥光他们的衣服
Strip them naked,
然后把他们埋到满是火蚁的沙堆里
Then bury them up to their necks
只露出脖子以上
On a huge mound of fire ants.
在一部老西部片里学的
Saw it in that old Western.
加入我吗
You with me?
要不用蝎子吧
Scorpions?
蝎子不错
Scorpions are good.
很好
Very nice.
酷  老爸
Damn, Dad.
看看这个
Check it out.
这是谁的
Who is this?
这是  小沃尔特  也可以叫他弗林
So, this is Walter Jr. Or Flynn.
他最近喜欢被叫做弗林
He likes to go by Flynn these days.
-妈  -干吗  我只是提供一点选择
- Mom...- What? I'm just offering the choice.
这位是施瓦兹夫人  想必你已经听说过了
This is Mrs. Schwartz, whom you've heard so much about.
很高兴认识你  弗林
Very nice to meet you, Flynn.
我也很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you, too.
沃尔特  看看谁来了
Walter.Look who's here.
见到你真高兴
Always nice to see you.
真是个惊喜
What a nice surprise.
看看你  看起来不错嘛
Look at you. You're looking good.
不过光头太惊悚了
Though a bald head is a bit of a shocker.
我知道这是为了我
I know it was for me.
你头型不错
You have a good shaped head.
-我可以摸摸吗  -当然
- May I?  - Oh, sure.
-为了好运  对吧  -对啊  要充满希望
- For good luck. Right?  - Exactly. Here's hoping.
我们要怀有憧憬  是吧
We could use some of that, huh?
施瓦兹夫人
Mrs. Schwartz?
谢谢你为我爸爸所做的
Thank you so much for what you've done for my dad.
真的太好了
It was a really good thing.
不用谢  真的
You're very welcome.
我们会想方设法报答你
We're going to find a way to repay you.
我们不奢求什么报答
We don't want to ever hear that.
我不想那么说
You know what?  I hate to say it,
但我真的得走了
but I really need to get going.
-太遗憾了  -你不能留下来吃晚餐吗
- That's too bad.  - You can't stay for dinner?
我希望可以  但不幸的是
I wish I could, but unfortunately
我怕会堵车
I have to try to beat the traffic.
我希望我们有机会能
Well, I hope we get a chance to...
畅聊一番
to catch up real soon.
但愿如此
Hopefully.
你的手袋
Your purse.
再会
Good to see you.
欢迎你和埃利奥特随时来做客
And you and Elliott are welcome any time. Really.
我个人
And I, for one, am gonna be much
也希望我们能常联系
better about keeping in touch.
-见到你真是太好了 -我也是
- It's so good to see you.  - And you.
认识你很高兴
Nice meeting you.
我也是
Likewise.
-再见了  -开车当心
- Bye now.  - Drive safely.
我在想
What am I thinking?
我该送她到车上
I should walk her to her car. Really.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
你能不能
What did you...
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
在那之前你可不可以
Can you not do or say
不要跟别人说
anything to anyone until then?
拜托
Please.
拜托了
我的钱在哪  贱人
Where's my money, bitch?
我不会好声好气问你的
I ain't going to keep asking nice!
你没傻吧  我要我的钱和货
Yo, all right?  I want my money and my dope!
我只是想说
I just want to say, man...
什么  你想说什么
What? What do you want to say?
我只是想说出来
I just want to go on record.
你打我打得太用力了
You hit me really, really hard.
我觉得我能看见重影
I think I'm seeing double.
或许我该去医院看看
Maybe I need to go see a hospital.
说真的  我可能脑震荡了
Serious, I might have a concussion!
别睡  宝贝
Don't fall asleep, baby.
-硬脑膜下血肿  -别睡着
- Subdural hematoma. - Don't fall asleep.
闭
Shut...
嘴
up.
把口袋里东西都掏出来
Empty your pockets.
把口袋翻出来  都放在桌子上
Turn them out, everything on the table.
快
Do it!
很好  转过身去
All right, turn around.
转身
Turn around!
把后面的口袋也翻出来  快
Turn out your back pockets.Come on.
好的  鞋子  放到这里
All right. Shoes. Give them here.
我告诉过你  猛男  我们一点也没留下
I told you, Diesel, we ain't holding any...
全磕完了
We shot it all.
一天半能磕掉一盎司那么多
Shot an ounce in a day and a half.
好吧  让我告诉你吧
All right, tell you what.
你们俩现在马上把它从屁股里掏出来
Both of you pull it out of your butts right now
不然我亲自拿上手电筒和钳子来找
or I grab a flashlight and some pliers and go exploring.
还等什么  快点
What's it going to be? Come on!
就是这样
There you go.
很好  快  放桌子上
All right, come on. On the table.
怎么  你拿冰毒
So what? You hold the crystal,
她拿海洛因  是吧
and she holds the H, huh?
分工合作
Division of labor.
好吧  这儿大概有八分之一盎司的货
All right, there's maybe an 8-ball here.
别的呢
Where's the rest of my meth?
说真的  她爽歪了把它们丢了
Yo, for real? She up and lost it, yo.
-你闭嘴  -闭嘴  贱人
- You shut up!  - Shut up, skank.
闭嘴  给我停手
Shut up! Stop it!
情况一点也没好转
This really isn't getting any better.
头盖骨都扭曲了
It's turning cranial.
你看见这把枪了吧  里面有五发子弹
You see this gun, huh? It's got five bullets.
两人每个膝盖骨吃一颗
One for each kneecap,
再给你的头盖骨额外一枪
Plus an extra round for your cranial,
就因为你太娇气了
for being such a pussy.
宝贝
Hey, baby.
过来  宝贝
Come here, baby.
快过来  宝贝
行了
All right.
你们俩再也别想嗑药了
You two are never getting high again.
我一辈子都不会让你们爽的
I will make it my life's mission.
针剂啊  冰毒啊  啥都别想了
Not another needle, not another ball,
在我拿到属于我的东西之前  一口都别想吸
Not one toke, not till I get what's mine.
我们会搞定的  绝不赖账
We got you covered, man, sure.
碰巧我们刚有钱给你
It just so happens we got
加上利息
your money, man, plus interest.
这才像话  还有利息  在哪
You're damn right, plus interest. Where?
后院
Backyard.
近在咫尺  后院
Right hand to the man, dog.
你去检查吧
Backyard. Go check it out.
-起  -你弄伤我了  痛
- Get...  - Hurting. Painful.
我和你爸爸
Me and your old man,
我们只是在玩个游戏  好吗
We're just playing a game, all right?
别动
Don't move.
快点
Come on!
看见了?
See?
我和那个贱人刚刚抬回来的
Me and the slit just boosted it.
她像只蚂蚁
She's like ant, man.
她可以举起相当于自己体重
She can lift a hundred times
一百倍的重物  不骗你
her own weight. For real.
我他妈要这东西干什么
What the hell am I supposed to do with this?
帮我把它砸开
Help me break it open.
把钱取出来  交货
Take out the money, get paid.
然后嗑药
Get high.
这是提款机
That's my bank.
那又怎么样  它有联邦存款保险
So?  It's FIDC insured.
这是场无人受害的犯罪
It's a victimless crime.
你他妈哪里搞来的这玩意儿
Where the hell did you get this?
杂货店  城那边的
Bodega. Way across town.
快进快出  顺利得很
In, out, like bam. It was smooth as silk.
什么  没人看见你们吗
What, nobody saw you?
有没有目击者  白痴
What about witnesses, dumb ass?
我们像风那么快  真的
We roll like the breeze, for real.
我们就这么进去了  一切顺利的很
All we did, we just walked in all smooth-like.
-根本没人注意  -真的没人注意
- Nobody even noticed.  - Nobody noticed?
-真的  -我告诉你
- For real?  - I'm telling you.
一场没有受害者的犯罪
A victimless crime.
上帝啊  你倒是快啊
Jesus! Come on already!
就快出钱了  我已经能感觉到了
It's about to give, man.  I'm sensing it.
你根本不知道你在做什么
You don't know what you're doing.
我以为你说过
I thought you told me
你偷过  大概  6个这玩意儿
you boosted, like, six of these.
偷过
Boosted.
但一个都没打开过
It's not like he ever got one open.
至少我一直很专注  根据一般规律
At least I got persistence.  The law of averages,
幸运数字是7
lucky number 7.
别听那个混蛋的
Don't listen to that skank.
别那么叫我
Stop calling me that!
我不是什么混蛋
I ain't no skank!
混蛋  混蛋  乌龟王八蛋
Skank, skank, skank ass skank!
好吧  我对天发誓
All right, I swear to God
我会直接崩了你们的脸
I will shoot you both in the face!
现在  保持冷静
Now chill!
你  继续开那玩意
You, get that thing open.
你他妈给我坐下  别乱扔东西
You sit the hell down, and no throwing things.
那个孩子呢
Where's the kid?
那个孩子  那个小屁孩
The kid! The little kid!
问我做什么
What are you asking me for?
你他妈算哪种妈妈?
What the hell kind of mother are you?
你也偶尔给孩子一顿
How about you feed the kid
体面点的饭如何
A decent meal every now and then?
给他洗个澡
Give him a bath.
再撒点爽身粉
Put some baby powder on him.
给他个像样的电视看看
Get him some decent TV to watch.
这算什么
What is this shit?
你是认真的吗
Are you serious?
你给我一针
You give me one hit, and I'll be
你想让我做什么样的妈我就做什么样的妈
Any kind of mother that you want.
猛男  如果我们每人都能来一点
Diesel, this whole thing would go easier
这事儿就会简单多了
if we all had a little taste, man.
滚一边去
Get out of the way.
Get out of the way!
所以你谁也没告诉
So you didn't tell anyone.
-你没告诉埃利奥特   -还没有
- You didn't tell Elliott.  - Not yet.
那是什么意思?
What does that mean?
就那意思
It means what it means.
这个决定  我还没法做
It's a determination I have yet to make.
好吧  够公平  不胜感激
All right. Fair enough.  I can appreciate that.
好吧  让我先说
All right. First let me say
我很后悔将你卷入此事
I very much regret involving you in this.
这是
This was...
这整件事其实
This entire thing was...
很不幸
unfortunate.
不幸
Unfortunate?
我深表歉意
And I apologize deeply.
请告诉我你为什么要那么做
Now please tell me why you did it.
这不是我们要讨论的问题
That's not really at issue here.
你说你有保险
You told me your insurance was
是骗人的吗
covering it. Was that a lie?
如果你不准备要我们的钱
If you won't take our money
这问题与你无关
This is not an issue that concerns you,
格雷琴  别问了
Gretchen, okay?
我很抱歉  但它确实与我有关
Excuse me. It does concern me.
有很大的关系
It concerns me greatly.
你告诉你的妻子和儿子
You tell your wife and son
我来付你治疗癌症的费用
that I am paying for your cancer treatment.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
我会和他们解释清楚的
I will clear this up with them.
斯凯勒脸上的表情
The look on Skyler's face...
她坐在那里  眼里噙着泪水
She's sitting there, tears in her eyes,
感谢我救了你的命
Thanking me for saving your life.
你为什么要那么对她
Why would you do that to her?
我说了  我会把这事说清楚
As I said, I will clear this up.
请
Just please
允许我以自己的方式和时间来处理这件事
allow me to do this in my own way in my own time.
好吗
All right?
我会向他们解释这整件事
I will explain the whole thing to them.
你在这么做的时候也请解释给我听
And while you're at it,explain it to me.
我并不欠你什么解释
I don't owe you an explanation.
我欠你一次道歉  而且我已经道歉了
I owe you an apology, and I have apologized.
我很抱歉  格雷琴
I am very sorry, Gretchen.
看  我已经道了两次歉了
There. I've apologized twice now.
我谦逊地向你道歉
I'm humbly sorry.
三次了
Three times.
让我直说了吧
Let me just get this straight.
埃利奥特和我愿为你付医疗费
Elliott and I offer to pay for
完全无偿的
your treatment, no strings attached...
顺便说一声现在依旧如此
an offer which still stands,by the way...
你出于自尊心拒绝了我们
and you turn us down out of pride,
然后你告诉你的妻子
whatever, and then you tell your wife
其实我们在帮你付医疗费
that in fact we are paying for your treatment.
没经过我们允许  违背我们的意愿
Without our knowledge, against our will,
你把我们卷入了你的谎言之中
you involve us in your lie.
然后你还能理直气壮地坐着
And you sit here and tell me
跟我说这事情与我无关
that that is none of my business?
大概就是这么一件事
That's pretty much the size of it.
你这是怎么了
What happened to you?
说真的  沃尔特
Really, Walt.
发生了什么?
What happened?
这不像你
Because this isn't you.
你觉得我是什么样的
What would you know about me?
在你心里
What would your presumption
我是什么样的
about me be, exactly?
我应该祈求你的捐助吗
That I should go begging for your charity?
然后你把支票簿一挥
And you waving your checkbook around,
就像挥魔棒似的
like some magic wand,
就可以让我原谅
is going to make me forget how you
当初你和埃利奥特背叛我的事情
and Elliott cut me out?
什么  事情并非如此
What? That can't be how you see it.
那是我的辛勤工作  我的研究所得
It was my hard work, my research, and
你和埃利奥特以此赚了几百万
You and Elliott make millions off it.
事情不是这样的
That cannot be how you see it.
-太好了  干得漂亮  -你离开了
- Good. That's beautifully done. - You left...
你总是一副天真无辜的样子
You are always the picture of innocence.
-你离开了我  -那副天真无辜的样子
- You left me.  - The picture of innocence.
-甜美而令人振奋  -你离开了我
- Just sweetness and light.  - You left me.
纽波特  7月4日那个周末
Newport, 4th of July weekend.
你  我父亲和我兄弟
You and my father and my brothers,
我回到房间
and I go up to our room,
你在整理行李  几乎不说话
and you're packing your bags,barely talking.
什么  难道这些都只是我的空想吗
What? Did I dream all that?
那是你的借口
That's your excuse...
依靠我的成果建造你的公司
to build your little empire on my work?
你怎么能这么对我说
How can you say that to me?
是你离开了
You walked away.
你抛弃了我们  我  埃利奥特
You abandoned us... me, Elliott.
小富婆只是累积你的资产
Little rich girl just adding to your millions.
我都不知道该对你说什么好了
I don't even know what to say to you.
我都不知道从哪儿说起
I don't even know where to begin.
我对你
I feel so...
很失望  沃尔特
sorry for you, Walt.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
孩子
Little man,
你饿了吗
you hungry?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
精虫  我抓住他了  我抓住他了
Spooge, I got him, I got him.
亲爱的  起来帮帮我
Baby, get up and help me!
既然你叫我坏妈妈
Call me a bad mother.
就让你看看坏妈妈是什么样的  混蛋
I'll show you a bad mother, bitch.
起来 操  拿好货
Get up, damn it! Get our dope!
该睡觉了
Bedtime.
到手了
Here we go.
现在谁是大哥大  是你吗
Who's the big tough guy now?Is that you?
你是老大吗
You're the big man?
有种打我啊 混蛋
Try and hit me now, bitch!
有种打我啊
Try and hit me now!
现在就打我啊  贱人
Try and hit me now, bitch!
我能问问你刚去了哪吗
Should I ask where you've been?
算了
Never mind.
过去就过去吧
We're long past that, I suppose.
格雷琴一个小时前打了个电话过来
Gretchen called about an hour ago.
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
说吧
Just say it.
他们停止给钱了
They're cutting off the money.
她到底说了什么
What did she say, exactly?
没说多少  就是
Not much. It was...
很突然  她说
Abrupt. She said...
大概说的是
something like...
"我很抱歉
"I'm sorry...
"不得不这么做  埃利奥特和我
"to have to do this, but Elliott and I
"无法再继续付
"can no longer continue
沃尔特的医疗费
to pay for Walt's treatment.
"你们一切都好"
"I wish you the very best."
就这些
And that was it.
她听起来像在道歉
She sounded apologetic.
我觉得  一切发生得很快
I guess, it was quick.
她马上就挂了电话
She got right off the phone.
我很震惊  但
I was so stunned, but...
我打回去  她没有接
I called her back, and she didn't pick up.
那么
So...
关于这事你都知道多少
what do you know about this?
今天下午她和我
She and I had a perfectly
聊得很开心
nice visit this afternoon,
然后你回家了
and then you come home, and all of
然后她突然就急着要离开
a sudden she's in a big hurry to leave,
然后你们俩就在
and then the two of you
车道上又聊了起来
are talking in the driveway.
你知道些什么我不知道的
What do you know that I don't?
你今晚去哪儿
Where were you tonight?
我开车去了圣达菲
I drove up to Santa Fe.
我和格雷琴在一起
I was with Gretchen...
当然  格雷琴还有埃利奥特
Well, Gretchen and Elliott.
今天  她就是
She just couldn't bring
不忍心告诉你
herself to tell you today.
我是说  她也不忍心告诉我
I mean, she couldn't tell me,
真的
either, really.
他们都在
There was a lot of...
经历一些
hemming and hawing and beating
混乱  挫折
around the bush from both of them...
告诉我们是什么
What... Tell us what?
很多
There was a lot of
商业用语掺杂其中
business phraseology being tossed around,
比如
Things like...
"现金短缺"和"周转不灵"
"cash poor" and "leveraged"
还有"季度收入下降" 什么什么的
and "quarterly decline," yada, yada, yada.
但是我觉得  他们其实是在说
But what they were truly saying, in my opinion...
他们破产了
They're broke.
你在开玩笑吧
You are kidding me.
我是说  现在经济状况很糟
I mean, the economy's in the toilet.
这我们都知道
We all know that.
这些大银行和
And all these big banks and...
范美妮以及
Fannie Mae and...
显然
Apparently,
头脑风暴相比于其他公司
Gray Matter is no more immune
也会受点影响
than anyone else.
就是说
That is...
天啊  也就是说
Jesus, that's...
她很可能刚刚想
She could have just...
亲自告诉我
told me herself.
他们是自尊很强的人
Well, they're prideful people.
听着
Listen.
不是我自私
Not to sound selfish,
但既然我们都到这一步了
but as far as we go,
我们得撑过去  好吗
we'll get through this, okay?
他们已经付了我的大部分医疗费
They've already paid for most of my treatment,
对吗
right?
我们能搞定
We're going to make it.
对吧  我保证
All right? I promise.
但是
And yet...
她还开着宾利车
she still drives a Bentley.
强撑面子还是
Keeping up appearances or...
我不知道  谁知道呢
I don't know. Who knows?
宝贝  这没道理啊
Baby, that don't make any sense.
当然有道理
Of course it makes sense.
每个保险箱都有它的弱点  不是么
Every safe's got its weak spot, right?
如果由你来设计一个保险箱
Say you're designing a safe. Where
你会把弱点设置在哪里
are you going to put your weak spot?
哪里都不放
Nowhere.
我要把它造的
I made it, like...
特别结实
strong.
上帝啊  放在底部  就是那儿
Jesus! On the bottom, that's where.
你把你的弱点放在底部
You put your weak spot on the bottom.
宝贝  海洛因让我
Baby, that H is...
犯困
bringing me down.
-你吸得太多了  我告诉过你 -我需要
- You took too much. I told you.  - I need...
我得振奋一下
I need to even out.
让我吸一口冰毒
Let me get a hit of that crystal.
不行  你已经吸掉了你那份了
Hell, no. You've lost your share.
拜托  宝贝
Come on, baby.
我只要一小口就行
It's all I need is just a little hit.
给我闭嘴  你这个混蛋
Shut the hell up, you dumb skank.
我正在努力集中精力
I'm trying to concentrate.
我不是混蛋
I ain't no skank.
我需要一个道歉
I would appreciate an apology.
什么
What?
我想要高潮
I am trying to take the high road here.
你准备给我吗
Are you going to do right?
听着  笨蛋
Listen to me, stupid.
我做某项很重要的工作正到一半
I am in the middle of some very important work.
我马上就能搞定了  明白不
I am on the verge here, all right?
所以闭上你的臭嘴
So shut your skank ass pie hole
过来帮忙  住嘴
and assist me and shut up!
我不是混蛋
I ain't no skank.
混蛋  混蛋  王八蛋
Skank, skank, skank ass skank!
王八蛋
Skank ass skank!
听着  混蛋
You listening to me skank?
你听到我说什么吗  混蛋
You hear me, skank?
你是个王八蛋
You are a skank ass skank!
我不是混蛋
I ain't no skank.
不要
Don't!
我不是混蛋
I ain't no skank.
你还记得躲猫猫吗
Remember peekaboo?
你能不能这样躲起来
Can you go peekaboo like this?
你可以闭上眼吗
Can you keep your eyes closed?
很好  太好了  好的
That's good. That's real good. All right.
你就像那样闭上眼睛
You keep them closed just like that.
我们将要玩一个小游戏
It's a little game we're going to play.
听着  你在这儿等着  好吗
Look at me. You wait right here. Okay?
这只是游戏的一部分
It's just part of the game.
你在这儿等  然后
You wait right here, and...
听着  就是别回头朝里面看
Look, just... just don't go back inside.
好吗  你就呆在这儿  好吗
All right? You stay right here. Okay?
祝你余生幸福  孩子
You have a good rest of your life, kid.